[
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named `Reeperbahn`?",
        "answer": "Hamburg"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is home to the world`s oldest casino?",
        "answer": "Venice -- The Theatre Saint Moses opened in 1638 and featured an area where patrons could gamble during intermission."
    },
    {
        "question": "Venice`s famed Bridge of Sighs connects two what?",
        "answer": "Prisons -- The bridge connects an old prison inside the Doge`s Palace to a newer one across the Rio di Palazzo."
    },
    {
        "question": "What animal is considered to be symbolic of Venice?",
        "answer": "Lion -- The Lion of St. Mark is a symbol that appears throughout the city. It honors St. Mark, who is the patron saint of Venice."
    },
    {
        "question": "What part of New York city got its name because it lies south of Houston Street?",
        "answer": "SoHo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oldest operating amusement park in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "Lake Compounce Amusement Park, Connecticut"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the largest rhino population?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many landlocked U.S. states are there?",
        "answer": "27"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the residents of the US state of Maine called?",
        "answer": "Mainers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Washington D.C. is located in which state?",
        "answer": "None, it is not part of any US state"
    },
    {
        "question": "Providence is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "Rhode Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the state of Texas?",
        "answer": "Austin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Coney Island is located on what island?",
        "answer": "It is not on an island. It is in Brooklyn"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which national capital can you find around 200,000 gers (traditional round tents) alongside other kinds of\u202fhousing?",
        "answer": "Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jarvis Island in the South Pacific belongs to what country?",
        "answer": "The United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "What bay does the San Mateo bridge cross?",
        "answer": "San Francisco Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the Hawaiian Islands is nicknamed the `Valley Isle`?",
        "answer": "Maui"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find the Cotopaxi volcano?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Nicaragua?",
        "answer": "Managua"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is the `pearl of the orient seas`?",
        "answer": "Philippines"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest lake in Central America?",
        "answer": "Lake Nicaragua"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city is known as the `City of Brotherly Love`?",
        "answer": "Philadelphia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Acadia National Park?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Cape Kennedy renamed to in 1973?",
        "answer": "Cape Canaveral"
    },
    {
        "question": "What European country`s highest mountain is Ben Nevis?",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find a soccer stadium that straddles the equator?",
        "answer": "Macap\u00e1, Brazil -- The city`s Est\u00e1dio Milton Corr\u00eaa soccer stadium`s center line lies exactly on the equator."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the second-highest mountain on Earth?",
        "answer": "K2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Liechtenstein?",
        "answer": "Vaduz"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is known as the `Land of Lincoln`?",
        "answer": "Illinois"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river flows through Utah`s Glen Canyon?",
        "answer": "Colorado River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What queen were the Virgin Islands named for in 1627?",
        "answer": "Elizabeth I"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the United States Virgin Islands?",
        "answer": "Charlotte Amalie"
    },
    {
        "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Nepal?",
        "answer": "Everest"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Champlain is located in Vermont and in which other state?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is known as the `Capital of the Silicon Valley`?",
        "answer": "San Jose"
    },
    {
        "question": "Trenton is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "New Jersey"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Buckeye State`?",
        "answer": "Ohio"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the first Punic War, Rome and Carthage fought over possession of what Mediterranean island?",
        "answer": "Sicily"
    },
    {
        "question": "Virginia`s Shenandoah River is the largest tributary of what other river?",
        "answer": "The Potomac"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city would you find the Hermitage Museum?",
        "answer": "Saint Petersburg"
    },
    {
        "question": "Burkino Faso is a former colony of which European country?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is known as the Old Lady Of Threadneedle Street?",
        "answer": "The Bank of England"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most northern capital city in Europe?",
        "answer": "Reyjkavik"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which landlocked body of water is located below sea level?",
        "answer": "The surface of the Dead Sea is a salt lake located about 1275 ft (0.39 km) below sea level."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Antarctica`s largest island?",
        "answer": "Alexander Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is home to Australia`s highest mainland mountain?",
        "answer": "New South Wales"
    },
    {
        "question": "What sort of food are `rollmops`?",
        "answer": "Fish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of fish is used to make `rollmops`?",
        "answer": "Herring"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country consists of the 4 main islands, Honshu Hokkaido Shikoku & Kyushu?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two small states are surrounded by Italy?",
        "answer": "San Marino and the Vatican City"
    }
]